Anne Burlak Timpson Papers, 1886-2003 (bulk 1912-2003)
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES 1886-98
  - Housing, 1972-94, undated, [see also Rent] (Box 24, Folder 19-22)
  - Hughes, H. Stewart, 1962-64, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Hunger, 1982-94 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Jamaica Plain, 1982-95, undated, [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Jobs with Peace] (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Jackson, Jesse, [seePolitics-National;SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES -Rainbow Coalition] (Box 25)
  - King, Mel, 1979-94, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Ku Klux Klan, 1978-95, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Labor, 1934-97, undated, [see alsoLegislation,Songs and poetry] (Box 25, Folder 6-8)
  - Latin America and the Caribbean, 1965-97, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Le Sueur, Meridel, 1978-96 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Legislation, [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-CPPAX]
    - General, 1975-95, undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Labor, 1954, 1982-95, undated (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Repressive, 1955-95, undated, [see alsoMcCarran Act,Smith Act] (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Unemployment, 1975-86, undated (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Lewis, Elma, 1971-86, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Lightfoot, Claude, 1955, 1978-91, undated, [see alsoSmith Act, McCarran Act] (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Luscomb, Florence, 1952-93, undated, [see alsoMcCarran Act, Peace] (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - May Day, 1936-41, 1986-97, undated, [see alsoCPUSA, Labor] (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - McCarran Act, 1950-66, undated, [see also Legislation] (Box 26, Folder 5-12)
  - McCarthyism, 1953-95, undated (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
  - Middle East, 1970-91, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Military, 1971-93, undated, [see also Gays in the military] (Box 27, Folder 4-5)
  - Morgan, Anna, 1980-96, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - North Atlantic Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), 1993-94, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Nuclear weapons, [see also Peace]
    - Arms race, 1976-86, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Disarmament, 1976-92, undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - First strike, 1983-85, undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Fort Collins protest, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Nuclear freeze/test ban, 1981-97, undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Nuclear war, 1980-86, undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Nursery campaign, 1945-46, undated (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - O'Connor, Jessie Lloyd, 1981-89 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Patterson, Louise and William, 1976-89 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Peace, [see alsoNuclear weapons, SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-CPPAX]
    - General, 1961-95, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Peace walks, tours, etc., 1981-93, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Persecution, 1930-90, undated, [see alsoLegislation, Civil liberties, McCarran and Smith Acts, SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--CPUSA] (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Philippines, 1975-96, undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Poland, 1981-93, undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Politics, [see also Songs and poetry, SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-CPPAX]
    - National, 1961-94, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Massachusetts, 1989-95, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Local, 1984-94, undated, [see also Boston, Jamaica Plain, Education] (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Privacy, 1993-94 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Racism, 1930, 1951-98, undated (Box 28, Folder 10-12)
  - Ravden, Sidney, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1980-89, undated, [see also Politics] (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Red-baiting, 1930-94, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Rent control, 1947, 1988-95, [see also Housing] (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Reynolds, Bertha, 1978-84, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Robeson, Paul, 1971-96, undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Sacco & Vanzetti, 1930, 1971-88 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Seeger, Pete, 1966-96, undated, [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE] (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Senior citizens, 1981-97, undated, [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--United Senior Association] (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Shields, Art, 1976-89, undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Smith Act, 1949-97, undated (Box 29, Folder 11-13)
  - Socialism, 1932-55, 1979-94, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Songs and poetry, 1951-94, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - South Africa, 1975-94, undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Southern United States, 1967-94, undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Soviet Union
    - General, 1977-97, undated (Box 30, Folder 5-6)
    - Anti-Soviet campaign, 1971-93, undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Dissolution: How Did It Happen? by Ernie Trory (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Soviet-U.S. relations
      - General, 1977-97, undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Cooperation, 1977-94 (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - Exchange, 1981-94, undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - Soviet hockey team, 1985-86 (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Trade, 1973-90, undated (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Spanish Civil War, 1937-49, 1978-82, undated, [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Abraham Lincoln Brigade] (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Strikes, 1886-97, undated, [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES--Autobiography] (Box 31, Folder 2-9)
  - Struik, Dirk, 1974-94, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Taxes, 1959-94, undated (Box 31, Folder 11-12)
  - Teixeira, Ed, 1972-84, undated (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Trade, 1983-96, undated, [see also Soviet Union] (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Unemployment, 1930-97, undated, [see also Legislation, SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--CPPAX] (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Unions, 1930-97, undated (Box 32, Folder 1-4)
  - Union women, 1976-94, undated (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Vietnam War, 1965-94, undated (Box 32, Folder 6-8)
  - West, Don, 1976-90, undated (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Winston, Henry (Winnie), 1971-94, undated, [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE, SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--CPUSA, SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES--Elections] (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Women, 1934-97, undated (Box 33, Folder 1-4)
  - World War II, 1944-45, 1981-94, undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Youth, 1978-94, [see also Hunger, Peace, Unemployment] (Box 33, Folder 6)
- SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS AND SLIDES 1912-98
  - Photographs, [see also SERIES VII. SCRAPBOOKS]
    - Anne Burlak Timpson, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 33)
      - Alone, 1931-98 (Box 33, Folder 7-8)
      - with family, 1912-98 (Box 34, Folder 1-6)
      - with others, 1930-90, undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Family, 1925-93 (Box 34, Folder 8-12)
    - Friends and associates, 1930-86, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Goodbye meeting for Eula Figuereido, Portuguese Club, New Bedford, MA, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Trip to Cuba, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Trip to Yugoslavia, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Veterans of Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 50th Anniversary Tour, 1986, [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Abraham Lincoln Brigade] (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous photographs, undated (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Slides
    - Anne Burlak Timpson and family, 1956-86, undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Trip to USSR, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Bill Timpson: football, 1965-68 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Commercial images of Leningrad, undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1963-67, undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
- SERIES VII. SCRAPBOOKS 1933-97
  - Naumkeag Steam Cotton Co. strike, 1933 (2 vols) (Box 36)
  - Arthur Timpson, World War II, 1943-45 (7 vols) (Box 37-41)
  - Kat Timpson, 1943-66 (Box 42)
  - Smith Act, 1954-58 (2 vols) (Box 43, Folder 1-2)
  - Boston history, 1956-57 (Box 43, Folder 3-4)
  - Family trips, 1957-67 (4 vols) (Box 44-47)
  - Bill Timpson, 1957-64 (Box 48)
  - ABT's trip to the Soviet Union, 1961 (Box 49)
  - ABT's 65th birthday, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 1-3)
  - Newspaper clippings and awards, 1987-97 (Box 50, Folder 4)
- SERIES VIII. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS 1961-2003
  - Audiocassettes (Box 51)
    - ABT w/ Kat Timpson Wright singing "Internationale," "They Grow Wild," and "Spread it on the Ground," 1979, [Digital files available] (Box 51)
    - Interview with Bill Schecter, 18 Dec 1980-10 Feb 1981 [5 cassettes], [Digital files available] (Box 51)
    - Interview with Kathleen Banks Nutter, 10 Jul 1998 [CD] (Box 51)
    - Interview with Kathleen Banks Nutter, 7 Aug 1998 [CD] (Box 51)
    - ABT interview with unidentified male for ABT's autobiography, undated [CD], [Digital file available] (Box 51)
    - Frank Gorman oral history, undated [CD; note: This material may not be copied. For copies, contact the Southern Labor Archives at Georgia State University.] (Box 51)
  - VHS cassettes, [Digital files available]
    - ABT at Boston Public Library and home, 1986 (Box 51)
    - Arthur Edward Timpson by ABT, 12 Mar 1987 (Box 51)
    - "Around Town with Bruce Arnold," ABT guest, 21 Feb 1989 (Box 51)
    - Interview, 11 Sept 1997, Rolls 7-9 [all 3 on single DVD], [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS-Interviews] (Box 51)
    - "With Heads Held High: The Story of the I.T.U.," 1997: ABT clips from 11 Sept 1997 interview [DVD] (Box 51)
    - "Birthday Greetings to the Red Flame," 1999 [DVD] (Box 51)
    - ABT memorial, 2003 [VHS] (Box 51)
    - "Stopping the Clock: A Time to Remember the Salem Pequot Mill Strike," 2004 [DVD] (Box 51)
  - Mini Digital Video cassette
    - Interview with Nicholas Burlak, 9 Aug 2002 [VHS] (Box 51)
    - Interview with William Timpson, 9 Aug 2002 [VHS] (Box 51)
  - Super 8, [Note: These reels cannot be played until they have been reformatted. Contact the Sophia Smith Collection for more information.]
    - Kat Timpson driving, snow shoveling, Jan 1961 (Box 52)
    - May Day, 1961 (Box 52)
    - Anne Burlak Timpson, Leningrad and Stalingrad, circa 1961 (Box 52)
    - Cape Cod, 4 Sept 1963 (Box 52)
    - Christmas, 1963 (Box 52)
    - "Sausage for Chuck," circa March 1964 (Box 52)
    - Christmas, 1964 (Box 52)
    - Bill Timpson's driving lesson, South Cape Cod Beach, Peter's Pond, Snake Pond, Wedding, Harvard, Mass., circa 1964 (Box 52)
    - Kat and David Wright, Feb 1965 (Box 52)
    - Christmas, 1965 (Box 52)
    - Swan's Island Nov. 1966 (Box 52)
    - Christmas, "Short of Ollie," "Lady in Park," 1967 (Box 52)
    - Kat Timpson graduation, Camping at Peter's Pond, 1960s (Box 52)
    - "Brothers & Kathy-graduating clothes," 1960s (Box 52)
    - Bill Mossing, undated (Box 52)
    - Departure, May Day, undated (Box 52)
    - Vacation in Maine at the Jones, undated (Box 52)
    - Lobsters in Maine, Pleasure Island, Bicycles in Park, Penny the dog, undated (Box 52)
    - Anne Burlak Timpson trip, undated (Box 52)
    - John Burlak and family, Odessa, undated (Box 52)
    - Henry Timpson, undated (Box 52)
    - Four unidentified reels, undated (Box 52)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Biographical materials (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Articles and newspaper clippings, 1931-32, 1956, 1982-92 (Box 53)
  - Awards
    - Rhode Island Labor History Society, 1990 (Box 53)
    - Mass. House of Representatives, 1991 (Box 53)
    - Family: Mike Burlak sketches, 1989 (Box 53)
    - Tributes: Poster, "Stopping the Clock…," 2004 (Box 53)
  - Correspondence
    - Buhle, Paul: advertisement, Encyclopedia of the American Left, circa 1990 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - "S": Don Searle to ABT, 20 May 1993 (Box 53)
  - Writings and speeches: autobiography research notes, 1932 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Organizations (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Communist Party of the United States of America (Box 53)
    - General: posters, programs, reports, 1962-1991 (Box 53)
    - Mass. District: finances, Boston area clubs, 1990 (Box 53)
    - People's Daily World: poster, "A Conversation with Vladimir Posner," 1987 (Box 53)
    - People's Weekly World: Poster, "Justice for Rodney King," undated (Box 53)
    - Seventy-fifth anniversary: calendar, 1995 (Box 53)
    - Youth Communist League, Dynamic, Apr 1988 (Box 53)
    - Jobs with Peace: poster, "Stop the Arms Race! Join Us at the Jamaica Plain Speak-Out," 1983 (Box 53)
  - Peace Fleece: brochure, undated (Box 53)
  - U.S. Council for International Friendship: newsletter and poster, 1982, undated (Box 53)
  - U.S. Peace Council: conference brochures, 1979-85 (3) (Box 53)
  - Wonder Woman Foundation: brochures, 1981-83 (Box 53)
    - Young Liberation League: Young Worker, 1979 (Box 53)
  - Subjects
    - Appalachia: "Pride in Appalachia: Music Crisp and Tart at Pipestem Festival," undated (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Berkman, Edith: letter and newspaper clipping regarding Berkman's hospitalization and Burlak's demands that Berkman be released, 1932 (Box 53)
    - Black liberation: advertisement, "An Attack on One is an Attack on All," 1 May 1970 (Box 53)
    - Bonner-Lyons, Pat: posters, "Bonner-Lyons for School Committee," undated (Box 53)
    - Civil Liberties: "James Roosevelt: Abolish the Un-American Committee," 1960 (Box 53)
    - Communism (International)
      - "Internationalism and the Soviet Union," Discussion Bulletin no. 5, 1957 (Box 53)
      - "A Letter to the Communist Party, People's Republic of China," by Gus Hall, undated (Box 53)
    - Du Bois, W.E.B.: "W.E.B. Du Bois: the 'logic of life' leads to socialism," People's Weekly World, 1994 (Box 53)
    - Education: brochure, Progressive Labor School of Boston, 1937 (Box 53)
    - Elections
      - President (Box 53)
        - Communist campaign articles, 1972 (4) (Box 53)
        - Jesse Jackson campaign literature, 1984-88 (2) (Box 53)
        - State elections/issues: poster, "Judith LeBlanc, Communist Party Candidate, State Senate," undated (Box 53)
        - Boston: poster, "Polly Halfkenny for City Council," undated (Box 53)
    - Hall, Gus: "The Last Comrade," Boston Globe Magazine, 1993 (Box 53)
    - Harrison, William H.: announcement, "Blacks in Boston" conference, 1989 (Box 53)
    - Hood, Frances and Otis: "Otis Hood, a Yankee the New Witchhunters Want to 'Get,'" The Worker, 9 May 1954 (Box 53)
    - Jamaica Plain: map, undated (Box 53)
    - King, Mel: campaign poster and newspapers, "Mel King for Mayor," 1986, undated (4) (Box 53)
    - Labor
      - "Phony 'Labor' Party Exposed as CIA Front," Daily World Reprint, 1975 (Box 53)
      - Southern Patriot, Jan 1976 (Box 53)
      - "Cambridge and the Great Depression: 1928-38," Dec 1976 (Box 53)
      - Local 509 Legislative Directory, 1991-92 (Box 53)
    - Latin America and the Carribbean: poster, "Heurte gehört uns GRENADA und morgen die ganze Welt!" undated (Box 53)
    - McCarran Act: poster, "The Nation, The World, is Fighting the McCarran Act," undated (Box 53)
    - Nuclear weapons: poster, "Danger-Nuclear War," 1980 (Box 53)
    - Peace
      - Poster, "Russians are coming," 1981 (Box 53)
      - Advertisement, "Peace…Please," Daily World, 7 June 1984 (Box 53)
      - Newsletter, International Workcamper, 1989 (Box 53)
      - Sign, "Urgent Appeal for Peace," undated (Box 53)
    - Persecution
      - "A Mind of Her Own: Americanism Wins," by Norma Nikrant, reprinted from Providence Evening Bulletin, 1 Mar 1957 (Box 53)
      - Poster, "Reward for Information Leading to the Apprehension of Jesus Christ," 1968 (Box 53)
    - Politics (National): campaign literature, District of Columbia statehood, 1979-83 (Box 53)
    - Racism: article, "Racism-Monopoly's Hammer Against All Workers!" by Gus Hall, 1975 (Box 53)
    - Red-baiting: "The Russians are Coming! The Russians are Coming!" 1982 (Box 53)
    - Smith Act
      - Poster, "Justices Douglas and Black Dissenting…" 1951 (Box 53)
      - Poster, "Episcopalians Lead Amnesty Appeal for Communists," 1953 (Box 53)
      - Pamphlet, "What Will Wellman do Now?" undated (Box 53)
    - Songs and poetry: union songs, undated (Box 53)
    - Soviet Union: Soviet-U.S. relations: Advertisement, "Friendship Worked Then…It Can Work Now," 1985 (Box 53)
  - Strikes
    - Poster, "The Strike" by Robert Koehler, 1886 (Box 53)
    - Book-signing event program, Strike of '28, 8 Oct 1993 (Box 53)
  - Teixeira, Ed: poster, "Register to Vote for Ed Teixeira," undated (Box 53)
  - Unemployment: "Call for Action on Jobs and Unemployment," 1971 (Box 53)
  - Union: ILUW Local 6 Bulletin, Mar 1983 (Box 53)
  - Union women: poster, "A Boston Premiere: Union Maids," 1976 (Box 53)
  - Vietnam War
    - Poster, "An Open Letter to President John F. Kennedy against U.S. military intervention in South Vietnam, 1972 (Box 53)
    - Brochure, People's Coalition for Peace and Justice, undated (Box 53)
    - Poster, "Why Demonstrate in May?" undated (Box 53)
    - Poster, "All For Vietnam!" undated (Box 53)
    - World War II: The Ack-count, 9 May 1945 (Box 53)
  - Youth: brochure, "11th World Festival of Youth and Students, 1978 (Box 53)
  - Photographs: ABT and others, 1932, undated (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbooks: railway maps of Scotland, England, Wales, 1943 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - International Peace Walk: Brochures, 1987-88 (2) (Map-case Flat File)
  - Union women: "Time and Motion" exhibit poster, 1991 (Map-case Flat File)
  - Original and print masters for audiovisual materials (Box 54-55)